JOSHUA ROCHOTTE

Phone: (732) 406-1929 joshjrochotte@gmail.com 1904 So. Central Avenue South Plainfield, NJ 07080

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dedicated, passionate Product Manager serving the life sciences industry for the past 4 years. Experience in leading teams to deliver highly functional, data science focused SAAS products. Looking to secure a place in a graduate program in Information Science

EDUCATION		
MI	Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey Data Science Technology, Information and Mana Beta Phi Mu Honors	May 2018 gement
Mini-MBA	Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey Biopharma Innovation	Dec 2017
BA	Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey Information Technology and Informatics Specialization in Game Design and Innovation	May 2017
BA	Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey Psychology	May 2017
HONORS AND AV	WARDS	
Member: Beta Phi Mu, Omicron Chapter International LIS Honor Society		Apr 2019
Dean's List		Dec 2016
PROFESSIONAL 1	Experience	
Medidata Solutions: Product Manager Execution of Program Priorities for Virtual Monitoring and Data		Mar 2021 to Present Science
Medidata Solutions: Product Owner, RBQM Execution of Program Priorities for 3 Analytics Software Tools		Apr 2020 to Mar 2021
Medidata Solutions: Implementation Consultant		Jul 2017 to Apr 2020

Advise Clients and Implement Life Sciences Software Products

TNT IP LLC: Test Engineer

Oct 2016 to Mar 2017

Research support on consumer electronics, summarization of findings

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information **Behavioral Informatics Lab** Professor Singh

2017

• Influenced Cooperation in Competitive Social Situations Project (Unpublished)

Gold Group Enterprises, Asbury Park, NJ Research Assistant

2016

- Documentation and Research on Mobile Behavior and Health Intervention
- Industry Interviews, Project Design and Application Prototyping

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information **EPIK Project** Professor Weber

2016

• Document Coder for EPIK research project

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information Jan 2018 to May 2018 **Teaching Assistant**, Retrieving and Evaluating 04:547:220

• Grading and Instructional Support, Office Hours and 1 on 1 Tutoring

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information Jan 2017 to Dec 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, OOP 04:547:202, 3 Sections

• Grading and Instructional Support, Office Hours and 1 on 1 Tutoring

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information Jan 2017 to May 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, IP3 04:547:400

• Grading and Instructional Support, Office Hours and 1 on 1 Tutoring, and course material development

PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED LECTURES

Professional Presentation, "Medidata Cloud Powers Clinical Trials of the Future" US FDA, Aug 2020

Lecture, "Big Data and Healthcare" Rutgers University, Apr 2018

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

A-CSPO Certification, Scrum Alliance, Apr 2021

Description: Advanced Certified Scrum Product Owner via Scrum Alliance

CSPO Certification, Scrum Alliance, Mar 2020

Description: Certified Scrum Product Owner via Scrum Alliance

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

AIPMM Apr 2021 to Present

Ambassador/Member

Scrum Alliance Mar 2020 to Present

PhUSE Jan 2019 to Present

Project Management Institute Jan 2018 to Present

Toastmasters International Jan 2018 to Jan 2020

LANGUAGES

English: Native Language

Spanish: Intermediate Listener, Novice Speaker

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, Java, C#, SQL, HTML/CSS/JS

Applications: Microsoft Office 365, Axure, IndigoDesign, Balsamiq, JustInMind, Jira, Confluence, Lucidchart, AHA

Skills: Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, Agile Development, UI/UX Design, Project Management, Workflow Design, Research and Information Management

OTHER

Data Science Passion Projects Computer and Console Gamer Avid Popular Science Reader Resume Review and Mock Interviewer Classically Trained Vocalist Amateur Cook

REFERENCES

Available upon Request